Guide to the Stanford University, News Service, Director's Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, News Service, director's records
1955-1967
SC0246
Stanford University. News Service.
2 Linear feet
Records cover three topics: Sigma Chi fraternity (issue of discrimination in membership 1965), Proposition 14 (written in 1964 to overturn California's Rumford Fair Housing Act, which prohibited discrimination on the basis of race and national origin), and student demonstrations and the McClellan probe (Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations headed by U.S. Senator John L. McClellan). Sigma Chi materials include correspondence, 1955-67, clippings and publications, 1965-67, and materials relating to a legal case against Sigma Chi in Colorado. The files on demonstrations and the McClellan probe, 1969, include news releases, drafts of administrators' statements before the McClellan subcommittee, news on SRI, President Pitzer's statements before the McClellan subcommittee, and letters from Stanford's legal service. The files on Proposition 14 include news releases, ads, clippings, newsletters, housing information, and articles on housing and property values. Major correspondents include Robert Beyers, Jack H. Friedenthal, Paul E. Kamerick, Kenneth S. Pitzer, and William R. Rambo.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer 1981.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Robert W. Beyers directed the Stanford news service from 1961 to 1990.
Description of the Collection
Records cover three topics: Sigma Chi fraternity (issue of discrimination in membership 1965), Proposition 14 (written in 1964 to overturn California's Rumford Fair Housing Act, which prohibited discrimination on the basis of race and national origin), and student demonstrations and the McClellan probe (Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations headed by U.S. Senator John L. McClellan). Sigma Chi materials include correspondence, 1955-67, clippings and publications, 1965-67, and materials relating to a legal case against Sigma Chi in Colorado. The files on demonstrations and the McClellan probe, 1969, include news releases, drafts of administrators' statements before the McClellan subcommittee, news on SRI, President Pitzer's statements before the McClellan subcommittee, and letters from Stanford's legal service. The files on Proposition 14 include news releases, ads, clippings, newsletters, housing information, and articles on housing and property values. Major correspondents include Robert Beyers, Jack H. Friedenthal, Paul E. Kamerick, Kenneth S. Pitzer, and William R. Rambo.
Access Terms
Beyers, Robert W.; Discrimination in education.; Discrimination in housing --California.; Friedenthal, Jack H.; Kamerick, Paul E.; Pitzer, Kenneth S., (Kenneth Sanborn), 1914-1997; Rambo, William R. (William Ralph), 1916-; Stanford Research Institute.; Stanford University. News Service. Director.; Greek letter societies.; Student movements--California--Stanford.; Students--Political activity.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Proposition 14
    - Materials (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Current Information (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - News Releases (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Ads (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Newsletters (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Property Values (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Opposit ion (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Housing Initiative (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Fair Housing (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Newsclippings (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - DEMONSTRATIONS, PRESIDENT PITZER, MCCLELLAN PROBE
    - Press releases, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Notes on SRI's counterinsurgency, 1969 Apr 28 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Senate resolution on SRI, 1969 May 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - News release, 1969 Apr 24 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence from attorney, Wolpman to Pitzer, 6/1969 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Statement of Paul E. Kamerick (ND) (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - McClellan Probe, Drafts of President Pitzer's speech, 6/1969 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Press release on President Pitzer's appearance in D.C., 7/1/1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Letter from President Pitzer to McClellan, 6/3/69 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence from ACLU to Robert Beyers, 5/28/1969 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - President Pitzer's statement before the U.S. Senate, 7/1/69 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Chronology of events (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Chronological summary of delonstrations at Stanford (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - President Pitzer's speech in vol 56 of the hearings on "Riots, civil and criminal disorders and disruptions on college campuses." (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Statement on a Black Panther, 6/24/1969 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - President Pitzer's response to demonstrations, 6/27/1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence from Apri 3rd, movement to the Academic Senate, 4/28/1969 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Sigma Chi
    - Legal matter, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Sigma Chi, court case, Colorado, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Court case Colorado (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Article, "When bias begi lls to cost money" by Terry Ferrer (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Congressional Record, 9/2/1965 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Newsclippings, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Newsclippings, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Newsclippings, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Newsclippings, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Newsclippings, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1955-1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, January - February 1965 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, March - April 1965 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, May 1965 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, June 1965 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, September - December 1965 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, January - June 1966 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, September - December 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - The Magazine of Sigma Chi (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Case before the Trustees of the California State Colleges, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 13)